Software Developer - Viktar Novikau (Виктор Новиков)



Contacts:

Email: vnovikau@gmail.com

Skype: vnovikau

Mobile: +7 953 171 42 03 Linkedin: Viktar Novikau

Overview:

Software engineer with 8+ years expertise and experience in design, development and testing of backend applications;

Skills Summary:

Programming Languages: C, Java, Go

Technologies/Frameworks: Spring Framework, Spring Boot, Hibernate, RabbitMQ, Elasticsearch,

Docker, JUnit, Mockito, SQL

Databases: PostgreSQL, Oracle DB, H2

Application Servers: Apache Tomcat, Jboss WildFly

Development Tools: Intellij IDEA

Source Control: IBM Rational Clearcase, SVN, Mercurial, Git

Bug tracking: JIRA, Redmine, YouTrack, Rally **Cloud Platforms:** Predix (CloudFoundry), AWS

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows

Education:

Brest State Technical University, 2005-2010, Bachelor of Engineering, Automation Engineer Technology

Professional Experience:

TaskData

Duration:	September 2016 – June 2018
Client:	General Electric
Project Description:	An MDM cloud based solution dedicated to manage master data for GE suppliers.
Responsibilities:	 business requirements analysis software design and development L3 support
Tools & Technologies:	Java SE, Spring Boot, Gradle, PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, Elasticsearch JUnit, Mockito, Git, Microservice Architecture, Predix

Tercom

Duration:	June 2014 – September 2016
Client:	"Toyota Motor"
Project Description:	A document management system dedicated to generate and process customs documents.
Responsibilities:	 business requirements analysis, communication with clients software design and development automated testing
Tools & Technologies:	Java SE, Spring Framework, maven, Jboss WildFly, Apache Tomcat, Oracle, JUnit, Mockito, SVN, Mercurial

LTD Fertoing

Duration:	April 2013 – June 2014
Client:	LTD Fertoing
Project Description:	"Intranet" a software based document management solution used internally by company staff.
Responsibilities:	software development, automated testing
Tools & Technologies:	Java SE, Spring Framework, Maven, Apache Tomcat, PostgreSQL, Mercurial

Ericpol Telecom

Duration:	July 2010 - December 2012
Client:	Ericsson
Project Description:	Ericsson VPN a software based solution to define a Virtual Private Network from existing physical telecommunications network elements.
Responsibilities:	 business requirements analysis and technical documentation writing software development test plan design, automated testing
Tools & Technologies:	Java SE, Apache Ant, bash/tcsh, IBM Rational Clearcase, Agile/Scrum